georgestaniland@gmail.com

0225109709

LinkedIn

GitHub

I am a resourceful developer with three years experience working across SaaS and agency-style companies. My expertise is in front-end development, working with Javascript frameworks to create highly manageable code bases that enable intuitive and snappy user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer — Freelance

FEB 2023 - PRESENT • AUCKLAND

- Developing websites using NextJs, MaterialUI, React Spring and Sanity Headless CMS
- Rebuilt website for Wellington-based Capital Scaffolding (launching soon), fixing major UI issues, migrating platforms, and improving SEO optimisation
- Developed custom Shopify site for U.S based Innovative Concepts

Front-end Developer — The Web Guys

JUN 2022 - FEB 2023 • AUCKLAND

- Created responsive website and web applications using NextJs and React with Typescript . Worked closely with the lead developer, contributing to projects in a CI / CD environment. Engaged in code reviews and peer programming
- Utilised a company library of shared React components to deliver web projects on time and on budget
- Technology: NextJs, Javascript, Headless WordPress, Material UI, GraphQL, REST API interface and consumption

Web Developer — Superstar Websites

MAR 2021 - JUN 2022 • WELLINGTON

- Agency role delivering websites & web-apps to clients, created responsive websites and tested them on a large range of viewport sizes
- Worked in a fully remote team, collaborating on 100+ project repositories under version control with Git
- Through extensive hands on experience I deepened my knowledge of PHP 7+, Chrome dev tools, SASS, SQL Databases, REST API consumption, CSS and HTML

Junior Developer Internship — Sailthru

NOV 2020 - FFR 2021 • WELLINGTON

- Working with the Principal UX Engineer, I worked on a new interface in Sailthru's React app. Utilised components from a design library, and created custom components
- Wrote Github actions to monitor repositories, and worked with semantic versioning in a CI/CD pipeline
- Contributed to Sailthru's design system, and Storybook library

EDUCATION SKILLS

React • Javascript • Typescript • Next.js • Node.js

PHP • GraphQL • Sanity CMS • Storybook

React Spring • Material UI • Sass • CSS • HTML

Headless and Traditional WordPress

Enspiral Dev Academy, April 2020 - August 2020

Bachelour of Design with Honours

Certificate of Web Development

Massey University, 2012 - 2016